A Guide to the Executive Papers of Governor Benjamin Harrison, 1781-1784
Library of Virginia
- Executive Papers of Governor Benjamin Harrison, 1781-1784., Extent: 19 boxes. (Box 1-19)
  Other noteworthy items include the following: bail bonds for individuals for their appearance at a trial for disaffection to the Commonwealth (1781 Nov. 30 & Dec. 1); certificate of qualification of Benjamin Harrison as governor & Thomas Lomax as privy councilor (1781 Dec. 1); list of persons in the care of William Rose, Keeper of the Public Jail, by whom committed, from whence, & offences (1781 Dec. 2); certificate of qualification of Sampson Mathews as a privy councilor (1781 Dec. 3); commission of Oyer & Terminer to Paul Carrington, Peter Lyon, & William Fleming authorizing them to hear and determine all criminal measures which the General Court could have heard & determined (1781 Dec. 4); ordinance of Congress ascertaining what captures on water shall be lawful in pursuance of the powers delegated by the Confederation (1781 Dec. 4); report of the situation of the Public Jail (1781 Dec. 15); certificate of qualification of Beverley Randolph as privy councilor (1781 Dec. 14); petition of inhabitants of Frederick County asking that the prisoners of war not be removed (1782 Jan. 8); order of the Council to reduce the regular troops under the command of Gen. George Rogers Clarke in the western country (1782 Jan. 18); certificate of qualification of St. George Tucker as privy councilor (1782 Jan. 22); certificates of qualification of Henry Tazewell & John Tyler for Benjamin Dabney to practice law in Virginia (1782 Mar. 12); return of artificers in the service of Virginia under Capt. James Anderson (1782 Mar. 29); articles of agreement between Robert Morris & George Eddy for the shipment of tobacco (1782 Mar. 30); proclamation of Gov. Harrison authorizing the Brig Mentor to transport tobacco to Charleston under a flag of truce in payment for advances made by Maurice Simmons to American prisoners (1782 Apr. 2); list of criminals tried by the General Court & sentenced to be hanged (1782 Apr. 5); intelligence respecting the murder of Indians on the Muskingum River (1782 Apr. 8); list of claims against the French army & Continental Army examined by Dudley Digges (1782 Apr. 16); articles of agreement between M. de Villemanzy & Dudley Digges for the settlement of claims of citizens of Virginia for damages done by the French Army between Sept. & Nov. 1781 (1782 Apr. 19); general return of all the damages sustained from the French Army at & about the time of the siege of Yorktown (1782 Apr. 19); bond of Jaquelin Ambler as treasurer of the Commonwealth (1782 Apr. 29); receipts for sundry claims against the French Army paid off by Dudley Digges (1782 May 4); return of officers, soldiers, sailors, & others of the state of Virginia taken & paroled by the enemy (includes name, rank, regiment, when taken, by whom, when paroled, by whom paroled, when exchanges, & remarks) (1782 May 7); act of the Maryland Legislature for the defense of the Chesapeake Bay (1782 May 23); certificate of qualification of James Monroe as privy councilor (1782 June 7); proceedings of the General Court providing a list of men sentenced to be hanged for various offenses (1782 June 15); certificate of oath of J. Banister as a member of the Privy Council (1782 July 3); orders of the Secretary of War to Capt. Guion for the withdrawal of French troops from Yorktown (1782 July 20); certificate regarding the appointment of William Tatham as assistant clerk to the Council (1782 Sept. 14); certificate of oath of General Robert Lawson as Privy councilor (1782 Sept. 20); extract of the journal of the House of Delegates re. the election of Benjamin Harrison as governor (1782 Nov. 20); report of commissioners, Joseph Nevill of Virginia & Alexander McClean of Pennsylvania, re. the extension of the Mason-Dixon line (1782 Nov. 28); certificate of qualification of Benjamin Harrison as governor (1782 Nov. 30); certificate of qualification of John Marshall as privy councilor (1782 Nov. 30); act of the state of Pennsylvania to prevent the erecting of any new & independent state within the limits of the Commonwealth (1782 Dec. 3); account of losses sustained by the inhabitants of Isle of Wight County by the British Army (1782 Dec. 5); a report of persons employed in the Quarter Master's Department (1782 Dec. 7); calendar of prisoners at December General Court (1782 Dec. 12); return of persons & their pay belonging to the State Laboratory (1782 Dec. 12); order of the Council re. the appointment of Thomas Meriwether as third clerk to the Council (1782 Dec. 17); proclamation of Benjamin Harrison for arresting British subjects in Virginia (1782 Dec. 20); articles to serve as a basis for a negotiation for the reestablishment of peace with Britain (1782 [N.D.]); proclamation of Gov. Harrison re. the return of public arms & other equipment to the county lieutenants by private citizens (1783 Jan. 13); proclamation of Gov. Benjamin Harrison for apprehending deserters (1783 Jan. 13); treaty of amity & commerce between the United Netherlands & U.S. (1783 Jan. 23); bond of William Goodwin as a privateer to operate against the commerce & trade of Great Britain (1783 Jan. 24); a bond of John Barrett as a privateer (1783 Jan. 29); list of soldiers who deserted from Winchester (1783 Feb. 7); a bond of John Cunningham as a privateer (1783 Feb. 21); broadside of articles agreed upon by & between Richard Oswald, Commissioner of His Britannic Majesty, for treating peace with the commissioners of the U.S. (1783 Mar. 19); proclamation of Gov. Harrison commanding civil & military officers of the state to obey the proclamation of Congress announcing peace with Great Britain (1783 Apr. 21); proceedings of a meeting of the officers of the State Line held at Richmond (1783 May 27); proclamation of Gov. Harrison prohibiting persons who have voluntarily left the country & adhere to the enemy or who have been expelled from the same from returning or remaining in the Commonwealth (1783 July 2); orders for the erection of three buildings at the Point of Fork on the ground where the state magazines were built & burnt by the enemy (1783 July 4); list of persons on the bill of attainder, banishment, & confiscation passed by the State of Georgia (1783 Aug. 19); treaty of amity & commerce between the U.S. & Sweden (1783 Sept. 25); proclamation of Congress recommending a day of thanksgiving (1783 Oct. 18); act of Massachusetts for granting to the U.S. certain imports & duties upon foreign goods imported into the state for the purpose of paying the principal & interest of the debt contracted in the prosecution of the late war (1783 Oct. 20); report of criminals convicted at the last session of the General Court (1783 Oct. 31); proclamation of Gov. Harrison disbanding the two state legions (1783 Nov. 4); return of men belonging to the State of Virginia who served in the 1st Partizan Legion (1783 Nov. 15); oath of qualification of Benjamin Harrison as governor (1783 Dec. 2); proceedings of the Board of Officers at Richmond (1783 Dec. 16); bond of George Rogers Clark & William Croghan authorizing them to receive amounts of land as the officers & soldiers may be entitled (1783 Dec. 20); speeches from the Shawnee & Wyandots re. peace and requesting a stop to the transport of liquor to their lands (1784 Mar. 2); certificate of qualification of William Nelson, Jr., as privy councilor (1784 Mar. 6); report of the grand committee appointed to prepare & report to Congress the arrears of interest on the national debt with the expenses for the year 1784 (1784 Apr. 27); quarterly return of ordnance & military stores from 1 February to 1 May (1784 May 1); proceedings of the Board of State Officers re. their claim for half pay (1784 May 11); proclamation of Gov. John Houston, Georgia, re. encroachments on the land of his state (1784 June 18); bond of George Savage as naval officer for the Northampton District (1784 June 26); certificate of oath of James Wood as privy councilor (1784 June 26); advice of Council that Col. Samuel Hawes & Col. Thomas Meriwether be appointed as commissioners to examine into all impositions in the settlement of the officers & soldiers accounts (1784 July 1); oath of qualification of James McClurg as privy councilor (1784 July 16); bond of Nathaniel Wilkinson, Miles Selden, John Harvie, Thomas Prosser, & William Foushee as commissioners for the better execution of the act of Assembly entitled "an act directing the sale of the public lands and other purposes in & around the city of Richmond" (1784 July 23); proceedings of the Board of Field Officers at Richmond (1784 Nov. 13); and an account of furniture purchased for the governor (1784 Nov. 25).
  Arranged in chronological order.
  - 1781
    - November 30-December 4 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - December 5-10 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - December 11-16 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - December 17-24 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - December 25-31 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - 1782
    - January 1-6 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - January 7-12 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - January 13-19 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - January 20-31 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - February 1-10 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - February 11-15 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - February 16-20 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - February 22-28 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - March 1-8 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - March 9-12 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - March 13-22 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - March 23-30 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - April 1-9 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - April 10-17 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - April 18-30 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - May 1-4 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - May 5-10 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - May 11-16 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - May 17-24 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - May 25-June 3 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - June 4-15 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - June 16-30 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - July 1-8 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - July 9-18 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - July 19-26 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - July 27-August 3 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - August 4-10 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - August 11-19 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - August 20-26 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - August 27-September 2 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - September 3-12 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - September 13-20 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - September 21-25 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - September 26-30 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - October 1-9 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - October 10-17 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - October 18-21 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - October 22-27 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - October 28-31 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - November 1-6 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - November 7-12 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - November 13-16 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - November 17-20 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - November 21-25 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - November 26-30 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - December 1-6 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - December 7-14 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - December 15-22 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - December 23-27 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - December 28-31 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Undated (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - 1783
    - January 1-4 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - January 5-9 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - January 10-17 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - January 18-26 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - January 27 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - January 28-31 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - February 1-5 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - February 6-11 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - February 12-21 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - February 22-28 (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - March 1-7 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - March 8-12 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - March 13-22 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - March 24-31 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - April 1-4 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - April 5-11 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - April 12-22 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - April 23-30 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - May 2-12 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - May 13-16 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - May 17-23 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - May 26-31 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - June 1-9 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - June 10-13 (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - June 16-23 (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - June 24-30 (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - July 1-5 (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - July 6-20 (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - July 21-31 (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - August 1-17 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - August 18-31 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - September 2-20 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - September 21-30 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - October 1-7 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - October 8-14 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - October 15-26 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - October 27-31 (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - November 1-8 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - November 12-20 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - November 21-29 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - December 1-12 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - December 16-31 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - 1784
    - January (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - February 1-4 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - February 7-27 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - March (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - April 1-14 (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - April 15-30 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - May 1-15 (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - May 17-29 (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - June 1-15 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - June 17-30 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - July 1-10 (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - July 13-31 (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - August 1-17 (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - August 19-30 (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - September 2-15 (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - September 16-30 (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - October 4-15 (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - October 17-30 (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - November 1-10 (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - November 11-20 (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - November 21-30 (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - Undated (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Oversized
    - 1782 (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - 1783 (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - 1784 (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - Undated (Box 19, Folder 4)